Philemon John

0806 977 9621 • Kubwa, Abuja • johnphilemon859@gmail.com • www.linkedin.com/in/johnphilemon/

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Technology leader with over 6 years of experience and an excellent track record of building, architecting and delivering highly reliable and scalable systems /software across a variety of areas and technologies, such as enterprise applications, voice, e-commerce, financial systems, etc. Professional skills in Inclusivity, accomplishing tasks with minimal supervision and relationship-building.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Community Manager – Abuja Developers Circle, Abuja

June 2019 - PRESENT

- Started and lead a community of software engineers consisting of more than 500 top developers within Abuja.
- Successfully organized online and offline seminars, workshops that mentored junior level developers on software development process, improved technical expertise to handle large scale projects.
- Launched a mentorship program that coached 30 interns and new intros into programming in the community.
- Successfully planned and organized with other team members the end of year tech summit for community members.

Founding Engineer – Hiredlance Digitals Ltd, Abuja

February 2018 - PRESENT

- Lead and empower the team of software engineers and quality assurance testers to develop and deliver highly scalable web and mobile applications.
- Managed redevelopment of internal tracking system in use by 125 employees, resulting in 20+ new features, reduction in save/load time and 15% improvement in operation time.
- Mentored and trained junior software engineers, improving their coding skills and product knowledge.

Software Development Manager – Fuller Housing, Abuja

September 2016 - April 2018

- Led a team of 10 engineers to deliver products with high efficiency and low infrastructure cost, resulting in increased revenue and customer satisfaction.
- Worked with cross-functional teams to deliver high-quality products within tight deadlines.
- Collaborated with the UI/UX team to improve a product's usability, leading to a 25% increase in user satisfaction.
- Introduced a new coding standard and best practices, reducing code complexity by 30%.

EDUCATION

MSc - Cybersecurity, Nasarawa State university, Keffi

Expected Graduation - July 2024

Bachelor of Science – Pure & Industrial Chemistry, University of Nigeria (UNN), Nsukka August - 2014

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Strong experience in recruiting, strategic planning, performance and project management, including mentoring/coaching other managers.
- Strong experience of leveraging technology to build scalable systems, programs, and teams without compromising quality.
- Excellent communication skills with a focus on team-building and customer relations.
- Strong leadership, attention to detail, and problem-solving skills to guide cross-functional teams across geographies.

USEFUL LINKS

Business website

www.hiredlance.com

Founded a growing Facebook community for Tech, Business and Startups in Nigeria.

https://www.facebook.com/groups/techbusinessandstartups

LANGUAGE COMPETENCIES

- English: fluent (speaking, reading, writing)
- Hausa: intermediate (speaking, reading); basic (writing)

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

Philemon loves challenges and technical problems, reading, writing and making researching. He is also very sociable person who values true friendship.

REFERENCES

References are available upon request.